(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T12:25:34.802349",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
高鳴る心臓に祈りを乗せて
Carrying a prayer within my throbbing heart,
曖昧な夢を描く
I sketch out an ambiguous dream.
幻想は想像のまま
Fantasies stay just as I imagine,
終われないんだ
and I cannot let them end.
答えを延々と探し続けて
Continuing to endlessly search for an answer,
何者かになりたくて
wanting to become somebody special.
滔々と降る夕立を
The pouring evening shower—
ただ眺めた
I just gazed at it.
優しく寄り添って
If you gently nestle close
心が晴れるのなら
and clear my clouded heart,
翼が生えたような気がして
it feels like wings have grown on me,
いつだって隣にいるから
because you're always right by my side.
だって言葉紡いで歌うことが
Because weaving words and singing them
わたしの運命だ
is my destiny.
世界にありふれた虚しささえも
Overwriting even the mundane emptiness of this world,
上書きして
overwriting it all!
路地裏に咲いた花のように
Like a flower blooming in a back alley,
願いを照らす
it illuminates my wish,
小さな光に憧れて
yearning for a small light.
名前を持たない歌なんて
A song without a name—
神様は認めてくれない
God won't acknowledge it.
一つ一つ枯れない花のように
Like flowers that never wither, one by one,
昨日の自分にさよならして
saying goodbye to yesterday's self.
溢れた涙
Overflowing tears—
うまく笑えなくてもいいからさ
it's okay even if I can't smile well.
だって理想は遠ざかってくばかり
Because ideals just keep growing more distant,
もう散々だよ
I've had quite enough of this.
どれだけ手を伸ばして叫んだって
No matter how much I reach out and cry out,
届かないの
it doesn't reach you.
望めばいつか叶うはずって
Believing that if I hope, it will surely come true someday,
信じてる
I still believe.
どうか歌よ響いて
Please, let my song resonate!
あぁ心臓の鼓動が今日も煩い
Ah, the beating of my heart is so noisy today.
高鳴る心臓に祈りを乗せて
Riding a prayer upon my racing heart,
曖昧な夢を描く
I sketch out an ambiguous dream.
幻想は想像のまま
Illusions remain just as I imagine them,
終われないんだ
Never able to end.
答えを延々探し続けて
Continually searching endlessly for an answer,
何者かになりたくて
Wishing to become someone,
滔々と降る夕立を
Gazing at the pouring evening shower
ただ佇んだ
as I simply stood there.
優しく寄り添って
If it gently draws close beside me
心が晴れるのなら
and clears my heart,
翼が生えたような気がして
It feels as though wings have grown upon me,
いつだって隣にいるから
Because you are always by my side.
だって言葉紡いで謳うことが
That's why weaving words and singing aloud
私の運命だ
Is my destiny.
世界にありふれた虚しささえも
Overwriting even the commonplace emptiness of the world,
上書きして
I overwrite it all.
路地裏に咲いた花のように
Like a flower blooming in a back alley,
願いを照らす
It illuminates my wish.
小さな光に憧れて
Yearning for a small light,
君の歌姫になれたらいいな
I hope I can become your diva.
Okey dokey 返事はいいけど
Okey dokey, your replies are fine, but
冗談なら笑えないよ
If it's a joke, I can't laugh.
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Congestion, ambiguity—which way are you facing?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand toward a mirage.
微熱のような夢物語
A fairy tale like a slight fever—
そんな光は見ない振りをしていた
I had been pretending not to see such a light.
ざわめく鼓動 まだ行かないで
A stirring heartbeat, don't go just yet.
幻じゃ嫌なんだ
I don't want it to be an illusion.
私を奪って
Take me away,
魅惑の dancing dancing night
In a captivating dancing, dancing night!
拡がって収まらない universe
A universe expanding beyond containment—
君の表情は私の森羅万象を
Your expression might rewrite all of my creation,
書き換えちゃうかも 責任重大ね
That's a heavy responsibility!
一切合切
Absolutely everything—
dance dance dance we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合ったゼログラビティ
Lost in a trance, intertwined zero gravity.
構わず
Never minding it,
dance dance dance just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness,
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even when you awake, don't leave me.
Maybe needy 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not in my right mind.
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your body heat.
誰彼そんなんじゃないから
It's not just with just anybody, so
独り占めして euphoria
Keep it all to yourself in euphoria.
気にしてないような言葉は装飾で
Words acting like they don't care are just decoration,
メイクのようには流せない
They can't be washed away like makeup.
360° 偽りだって
Even if 360 degrees of it is a lie,
隠しきれないような
In a way that can't be fully hidden—
私に構って嬉しいなんて
Being happy that you pay attention to me...
crazy crazy love
摩天楼から連れ去って
Carry me away from the skyscrapers!
君の表情は私の深層心理を
Your expression might replace my deep subconscious,
すり替えちゃうのよ 責任重大ね
That's a heavy responsibility!
過ぎ去ったネオン
Neon lights that have passed by,
残像 shooting star
An afterimage shooting star.
グライダーみたいに漂えば
If I drift along like a glider,
幸も不幸もなかった
There was neither happiness nor misfortune.
指先でまた君を探している
With my fingertips, I am searching for you once more.
その声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear your voice!
私に構って
Pay attention to me,
教えてよ 恋の先を
And tell me where this love leads!
拡がって収まらない universe
A universe expanding beyond containment—
君の存在は私の将来までも
Your presence steps right into my future,
踏み込んだのよ 付き合ってよね
So go out with me, won't you?
一切合切
Absolutely everything—
dance dance dance we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合ったゼログラビティ
Lost in a trance, intertwined zero gravity.
構わず
Never minding it,
dance dance dance just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness,
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even when you awake, don't leave me.
構わず
Never minding it,
dance dance dance just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま 目を覚ましても離れないで
Leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness, even when you awake, don't leave me.
みんな！今日は誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
コメントも見えてるよ！
I can see your comments, too!
最初に聴いてもらったのが「Diva」、「Dancing Reed」でした！
The first two songs you heard were "Diva" and "Dancing Reed"!
え、この2つの曲は、あのフェスと、あと去年のね、ドラマの主題歌に使わせて頂いて、すごく思い出に残っているので、最初に2曲歌ってみようかなと思って選びました。
These two tracks were used for that festival and last year's drama theme song, holding so many precious memories for me, so I chose to sing them right at the start.
そして、今回はですね、ときのそらお披露目誕生日2026……ときのそらじゃないよ、ときのそらだよ！で
And this time, it's Tokino Sora's debut birthday 2026—wait, not Tokino Sora, I mean Tokino Sora! Right, so...
ええ みんなのつぶやきを待っているので たくさんつぶやいてほしいな
I'm waiting for everyone's tweets, so please tweet a lot!
それに入るときはね、
And when you participate,
ねえ
right?
そして今回のテーマは、周年を象徴する「無限」をモチーフに宇宙や星をステージに散りばめて、中毒性のあるビートとリズムの曲で絡めた、
And our theme this year is "Infinity," symbolizing our anniversary, featuring a stage scattered with stars and space, woven together with addictive beats and rhythms—
ええ、デジタルパルスライブです！
a digital pulse live!
デジタルパルスライブです！
A digital pulse live!
こちらね、大きな天球が曲によってどう変わるのかを見ていてください。
Take a look at how this large celestial sphere changes depending on the song.
そしてね、今年のノンノンはええ、5つなのでぐるぐる回転してます。ぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐる
And this year, there are five Non-nons, so they're spinning round and round! Round and round, round and round...
そしてよ、空にはそらざうろすもいるよ。
And hey, up in the sky, there's also a Sorasaurus!
そらざうろすはね、なんとね、炎を出せるようになりました。
The Sorasaurus, you know, can now breathe fire!
ぽー
Pew!
暗きもね、ちゃんと暗きもざもあるんですけど、やれるかな？
And we also have the Ankimo version, can we do it?
もちろん、あと今年も新章のお披露目を告知したゲストと、あと、どんな曲を披露するのかを楽しみにしていてくださいね！
Of course, look forward to our newly announced guest for the new chapter reveals, and what songs we'll be performing!
そして、次に行く前にフッチーお披露目最初に出しちゃいましょう！
And before we move on to the next part, let's reveal Futchi right away!
カメラさん、上を向いてください。
Cameraman, please look up.
はーい、というわけで、
Ha~i! So, that's why...
新しいクナゲヘヤー、新髪型お披露目です！
It's the reveal of my new hair, my new hairstyle!
それでは早速、ゲストパートに行ってみよう！かわいい、ありがとー！おー、かわいいありがとー！白金さんしいっぱいコメントしてってね！
Now, let's head straight to the guest part! So cute, thank you! Oh, so cute, thank you! Shirokane-san, leave lots of comments!
最初のゲストはこの人です！
Our first guest is this person!
星の降るたびに 君に逢えるたびに
Every time stars fall, every time I meet you,
恋々だった夜は銀河系だ
nights filled with deep love are like a galaxy.
今夜は銀河系だ
Tonight is a galaxy!
今夜をそらの愛をライトが鮮やかに眩しいから
Tonight, Sora's love, your light is dazzlingly bright,
街の音を空隙取り、遠くに消えようかふたり
leaving behind the city's sounds, let's fade away together into the distance, you and I.
知らない暗い夜、暮らしが心を満たすから
In an unfamiliar dark night, daily life fills my heart,
この肌だけ、君だけ、そっと夜に星屑をかける
this skin alone, you alone, gently scattering stardust into the night.
見つめあう表情、照らしてミョウジョウじゃなくにか
Gazing at each other's expressions, illuminating them, not the morning star, but...
見上げた心臓、宇宙が違って光る、掴ぶほどに踊って
A heart looking up, the universe shining differently, dancing as if grabbing it,
孤独ごと抱きしめて二人を隠して恋は銀河系だ
embracing every bit of solitude, hiding the two of us—love is a galaxy.
恋は銀河系だ 恋は銀河系だ 恋は銀河系だ
Love is a galaxy, love is a galaxy, love is a galaxy!
お、同じペースで泳ぎだすペーブメント、酔いと酔いで繋ぐ浅い一瞬だけのダンス
Swimming at the same pace on the pavement, a brief dance connected only by intoxication,
あなたと私の魂の行方は、はるか遠く先を差した
the destination of your soul and mine pointed far, far ahead.
結ぶ、おりおんの、はえいの、星が、真っすぐに燃えるから
Connecting, Orion's fly, stars burning straight ahead,
親だけ、乗り込もう、夜は満点の王族、だから
just parents, let's board, the night is a starry royal family, so
見つめあう表情、隠してミョウジョウじゃなくにか
Gazing at each other's expressions, hiding them, not the morning star, but...
その時までの気持ちが道だって探り出せるから
Because I can figure out the path of feelings up until that moment,
生まれたままの衝動、隠してミョウジョウじゃなくにか
the raw impulse of birth, hiding it, not the morning star, but...
私の、あなたと、鼓動が、ドキドキって高鳴る、終わるほどに踊って
My heartbeat thumping wildly with yours, dancing until it ends,
最後の、涙が、星と、星が、ぶつかって
the final tears, stars crashing against stars,
音を立てて、君は銀河系だ
making a sound—you are a galaxy!
いつだって愛を歌うんだから
Because I'll always sing of love!
はーい！
Hi there!
というわけで最初のゲストは
So, our first guest is...
白上ちゃんだよー！
Shirokami-chan!
こんにちは！
Hello!
時の…白上です！
Tokino... Shirokami!
時のじょおりんになっちゃった！
I became Tokino Jyorin!
本当に今日はそらちゃん
Truly, today, Sora-chan,
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
happy birthday to you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
すごいね、服装
That outfit is amazing.
そらちゃんという歌姫にお揃いできると聞いて
When I heard I could match with songstress Sora-chan,
出せるものは全部出していこうと思います。
I decided to put everything I've got out there!
そう、そういうことだったんだ。
Oh, so that's what it was.
待って、これで、ちゃ、チャンネルバンされちゃった…
Wait, will this get my channel banned...?
大丈夫ですか！大丈夫ですか！胸が苦しくなってきました！
Are you okay? My chest is getting tight!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
そらちゃん、クラーゲンさんには、注射があるって聞きます。
Sora-chan, I heard that Kuragen have injections.
注射？特製ヨシを是非頭でごズンと後ろにさせていただませんか？
An injection? Won't you please let me drive the special stinger into the back of your head?
ぶっごつん！
BAM!
お、お、倒す、倒れるじゃん！
Woah, I'm falling over!
すごい効いてきました！効いてきた？
It's really taking effect! It's taking effect?
皆さん、そらちゃんは変わりました。
Everyone, Sora-chan has changed.
毒針をまとった女に変わったんです！
She's changed into a woman wearing a poisonous stinger!
でも、そう、私強くなったから！そらちゃんは毒針を持ちたくて可愛いクラーゲンになったんですか？
But, yeah, I got stronger! Sora-chan, did you want a poisonous stinger and become a cute Kuragen?
いやいやいや、私やっぱアイドルといえばこういう可愛い髪の人が多いかなと思って、そういうアイドルっぽい髪型にしたいなと思ってたんだよね。
No, no, no! I thought idols usually have cute hairstyles like this, so I wanted an idol-like hairstyle.
はあ、そらちゃんって聞いてください。私だってアイドルでしかないし、歌姫でしかないのに、ディーバっていう曲もありますけど、今もアイドルであろーとこうなんか、なってるのに…
Haah, Sora-chan, please listen. I'm nothing if not an idol, nothing if not a songstress, and even though I have songs like "Diva", why am I still trying to be an idol like this...
努力してくれる姿がもう大好きで、食べたいくらい、食べちゃうの？シナモンロール会いたいですね。
I love the sight of you working hard so much I could eat you up! You'd eat me? I want to meet Cinnamoroll.
見て、カメラさん、見て見て！これはシナモンロール！シナモン、あ食べられてる、食べられてる。
Look, camera person, look! This is Cinnamoroll! Cinnamon... Ah, she's being eaten!
首の匂いどう？ あ、いい匂い。私からも匂いするよ。
How does the back of my neck smell? Ah, it smells good. I smell good too.
はい、ということで、今日はパンツない発言を心がけていきます。もうすでに結構白ちゃんワールドくさくしてますけど。
Right, so today I'll keep in mind not to make panty remarks. Although Shiro-chan's world is already pretty explosive.
この、なんかこんな、大好きなそらちゃんのこんな私とそらちゃんたちと一緒に呼んでもらえると思わなくて、はーい。あ、ざ、残念ぶりだよ。
I didn't think I'd be invited along with everyone else for Sora-chan's beloved self... Haah. Ah, it's been 3 years.
3年ぶりの元カノです。そらことかじゃない！そらともさんと一緒に、一緒に、一人占めしないのでめでていきましょう。
It's my ex-girlfriend after 3 years. Not Sora-koto! Let's celebrate together with Soratomo-san without monopolizing her.
今日はそらともさんに、あの白の期待の意味をわからせたいと思います。そらちゃん立ってください。
Today, I want to make Soratomo-san understand the meaning of Shiro's expectations. Sora-chan, please stand up.
はい！さあ、3、2、1！
Yes! Now, 3, 2, 1!
バニーガールです！この服装でいいの？ねえ？
A bunny girl! Is this outfit okay? Hey?
千紫万紅、そらちゃん新衣装のバニーショウプレゼントしに来ました。ありがとうございます！どうですか？可愛いよ、バニーガールも可愛いよ。
I came to present Sora-chan's new bunny show outfit. Thank you! How is it? It's cute, the bunny girl is cute too.
兎咲さんってマネー発足してるのでちょっとはーはーしてもらって。
Bunny-san is in estrus like a mannequin, so please pant a bit.
あ、私からも心いっぱいだよ。
Ah, my heart is full too.
そうだよ、そらちゃんといえば！
That's right, speaking of Sora-chan...
尻尾は、さ、ちょっと置いてもいいですか？いいよ？ちんちん
Can I put my tail down for a bit? Sure.
ちんちん、大嫌！何？白発出所が止まらないの！
Big trouble! What? Shiro's outbursts won't stop!
そそろおうちに帰ります。
It's about time I go home.
配信の月 からみんなを見守ってます。この後も楽しんでね！楽しみよ！ありがとう！
I'll be watching everyone from the moon of streaming. Enjoy the rest of the stream! I'm looking forward to it! Thank you!
白ちゃんワールド炸裂で楽しかったね！なんだこれって言わないでみんな！ねえ？
Shiro-chan's world was in full blast and so fun! Don't say "What is this?", everyone! Right?
でも、相変わらずの白ちゃんで私、一緒に歌えてとっても楽しかったです！マイペースだね、ねえマイペースだよ。
But, as always, Shiro-chan... I had so much fun singing together with her! She's at her own pace, right?
私もマイペースだから、いいコンビってことだ！
I'm at my own pace too, so we make a good duo!
というわけで、続いてのゲストに行きましょう！この人です！
So, let's move on to our next guest! It's this person!
ときのそら お披露目誕生日2020
[Tokino Sora Birthday Party 2020]
GUEST 緋月ゆい
[Guest: Higure Yui]
全部全部アンタのせいだ
It's all, all your fault.
ヘドが出るくらいにウザったいわ
It's so annoying I could throw up.
何かに縋って諂って
Clinging and scraping to something,
期待したアタシがバカだった
The hopeful me was an idiot.
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
An eight-way beauty pleasing everyone,
それ故にアンチな一生gimme
Hence, an anti-type gimme.
浅いキャパシティ 毎度おおきに
Shallow capacity, always mediocre,
つまるとこ人生ずっと地味
A boring life, forever mundane.
「憎たらしい！」「痛々しい！」
"Hateful!" "Pathetic!"
無視 出来ないのが一層
Ignorance is impossible, making it even worse.
腹立たしい 苛立たしい
Irritating, frustrating,
そろそろ飽きた 自画自賛に
Sick of self-praise, getting tired of it soon.
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of a like is antipathy,
繋がれた証
Proof of a connected bond.
切り離せない関係 疎らしてしまいたいわ
An inseparable relationship I want to shake off.
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is so-called hate speech,
匿名性の声明を生命に載せてんだ
Putting anonymous declarations into life.
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度に痙攣
An endless silence, spasming as it gets closer.
赤信号にずっと順々です。
Always staying compliant with the red light.
大体アナタのこと アタシ
Basically, it's all about you and me!
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイ ダイキライ
Dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-hating you!
omg 情けない 最早 バイバイバイ バイバイしたい
Omg, I've had enough, I wanna say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye.
脳内も予測不得 故に
In-brain predictions are impossible, thus,
解解 解 解解はない
Solution, solution, solution, solution... There is none!
どうだい？ アタシのこと アナタ
How is that? About you and me,
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイ ダイキライになった？
Have you started dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-hating me?
ぁ 弊害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, having harm and zero gain, nothing, not see.
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if we line up "what ifs," it's just smiling faces.
i miss youって近づいた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
"I miss you," drawing closer, the end is a silly mistake, a silly mistake.
センセーク反対教師
Cent-sec anti-role model,
後味一生 消えてくんないわ
An aftertaste that will never disappear for life.
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good girl.
笑顔振りまき パラパラいい子ね
Scattering smiles, scatter-scatter, good girl.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But, but, what is your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？ 笑 はぁ。
Can't even tell good from evil? Ha, lol.
減点方式で 取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Caught in a deduction-based recycling environment,
生代、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞かれないわ！って
"Life hurts! Hurts! Hurts!" cannot even be heard!
当然の報いにクラッちまった
Crashing down from the natural reward,
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors.
実のところ 依存は両方です
In reality, dependency goes both ways.
シャットダウンしても 纏り付く
Even if you shut down, clinging on,
己の弱さが 不甲斐ない
Our mutual weakness is inexcusable.
全部全部 アタシのせいって
It's all, all because of you,
反吐が出るくらいに 止まんないわ
So bad I could puke, I won't stop.
いっその事 切り離せた方が 楽なのに な
Honestly, cutting ties would be so much easier, but...
大体アナタのこと アタシ
Basically, it's all about you and me!
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイ ダイキライ
Dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-hating you!
omg 情けない 最早 バイバイバイ バイバイしたい
Omg, I've had enough, I wanna say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye.
脳内も予測不得 故に
In-brain predictions are impossible, thus,
解解 解 解解はない
Solution, solution, solution, solution... There is none!
どうだい？ アタシのこと アナタ
How is that? About you and me,
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイ ダイキライになった？
Have you started dai-dai-dai-dai-dai-hating me?
ぁ 弊害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, having harm and zero gain, nothing, not see.
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if we line up "what ifs," it's just smiling faces.
i miss youって近づいた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
"I miss you," drawing closer, the end is a silly mistake, a silly mistake.
センセーク反対教師
Cent-sec anti-role model,
後味一生 消えてくんないわ
An aftertaste that will never disappear for life.
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good girl.
笑顔振りまき パラパラいい子ね
Scattering smiles, scatter-scatter, good girl.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But, but, what is your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？ 笑 はぁ。
Can't even tell good from evil? Ha, lol.
減点方式で 取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Caught in a deduction-based recycling environment,
生代、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞かれないわ！って
"Life hurts! Hurts! Hurts!" cannot even be heard!
当然の報いにクラッちまった
Crashing down from the natural reward,
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors.
実のところ 依存は両方です
In reality, dependency goes both ways.
シャットダウンしても 纏り付く
Even if you shut down, clinging on,
己の弱さが 不甲斐ない
Our mutual weakness is inexcusable.
全部全部 アタシのせいって
It's all, all because of you,
反吐が出るくらいに 止まんないわ
So bad I could puke, I won't stop.
いっその事 切り離せた方が 楽なのに な
Honestly, cutting ties would be so much easier, but...
[Music]
やったー！乾杯！
Yay! Cheers!
乾杯！
Cheers!
はい！
Hi!
改めてね、Neo-Porte所属の夜図きゆです。
I'm Yuzuki Choco, belonging to Neo-Porte.
そらさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！来てくれてちゅえーんじ！おめでとう！
Thank you! Choco-chuen, happy birthday!
去年ぶり！
It's been a while!
そうだよね、去年はね、ちょっとね、
Yeah, last year we...
はい。
Yeah.
メッセージだけと、あの、あの、どうも。
We only had messages...
あの、去年は本当に申し訳ありませんでした！
Really, I'm so sorry about last year.
いや、そんな、そんな、そんな！
No, no, no!
いや、そのメッセージでもね、すごくみんな「うおおっ」てなってて、
Wait, Choco's messages...
うれしかったりさよ。
It was so cute, you know.
すごいガラガラ声でね、去年は、あの、参加させていただいたんですけれども、
It was in that garbled voice.
今年はリベンジができてとっても嬉しいです。
This year, I'm so happy I got my revenge!
やったリベンジだ！
Yay, revenge!
呼んでいただいて嬉しいです。ありがとうございます！
I'm so glad you invited me, thank you so much!
こちらこそ！
And thank you too!
今回の曲もね、私が選んだんですけども、
For this song, too, we chose it together.
やっぱり、あの、Yuzuki Chocoといえばかっこいい声、
You know, Yuzuki Choco has such a cool voice,
っていうのがね、すごく私の中で、あの、頭の中であって、やっぱかっこいいよ。
And that was really in my head.
なので、このね、デュエットっていうのもあるので、この曲をぜひ一緒に歌いたいと思って。
So, we have this duet version,
嬉しい！いたしました。
I'm so happy!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
いや、あの、歌うの超難しかったんですけど、
Well, singing it was super difficult.
どちらかというとダンスが、普段あんまりしないので、
Especially since I don't usually dance much.
そうだよね！
Right?
はい。
Yeah.
ちょっとチョコさんとダンスレッスンなどをね、
So, I took dance lessons with Choco-san...
この本番に向けて
Preparing for this main performance,
で、振り付けはめちゃくちゃ速くてびっくりした。
Wait, the choreography was so fast it shocked me!
ちょっとね、ああって言いながらね、
Just like, "Ah..." while saying that,
ターンが本当に体感がなさすぎて、ああって、ああって何度も湯もよろけてですね、
My turns really didn't feel balanced at all.
大変だったんですけど。
It was tough.
いや、でも本番は完璧だったんじゃないの？
Well, but the main performance was perfect, wasn't it?
よかった。よろけたくて、めちゃ頭でよろけちゃねえ、よろけちゃねえと思いながら、
I was so happy it made me want to stagger around, thinking, "Don't stagger, don't stagger,"
もうそらさんが完璧なんでダンス。
Sora-san is just perfect, you know.
いやいやいや、そんなことない。いやいやいや、そんなことない、そんなことない。
No, no, no, not at all!
まさかひづきちゃんもレッスンしてもらえると思わなかったの
I never thought Hizuki-chan would get lessons too!
だから、その、せっかくダンスもあるんですけどって
So, when they told me there would be dancing,
言ったときに、はい。
I said, "Oh!"
いや、ダンスはちょっと…踊れるかなと思ったから
I thought, "I wonder if I can dance..."
ぜひ、と思いましたって。
So I thought, "I'd definitely love to!"
普段ね、こう、こう、右手でどうにかしてるんで
Normally, you know, I manage somehow with my right hand...
手持ちマイクで右手でどうにかこう、喋ったりしてたんですけど
With a handheld mic in my right hand, talking and getting by,
今日はダンスに挑戦できたのがすごい自分的にもすごい嬉しかったですね。
but today, being able to challenge myself with dancing made me really happy.
めちゃくちゃかっこよかった！
You looked super cool!
いやいや、一緒に踊れて超嬉しかったんで。
No, no, I was super happy to dance together!
いや、本当、嬉しかったー。
Seriously, I was so happy!
どうでしたか、どうだった？
How was it? How did it go?
どうでしたか？頑張ったでしょ？
How was it? Did you work hard?
頑張ったぞ！頑張ったよー！
I worked hard! I really did!
そんな感じで、この後もね、まだライブがあるということなので、この後もぜひ頑張ってください！
With that said, there's still more of the live stream coming up, so please do your best for the rest of it too!
頑張るよ！
I will!
応援してまーす！ありがとう！
I'm cheering you on! Thank you!
はい、ということで、お披露目日でした！ありがとうございました！
Right, so that was the debut day! Thank you very much!
素敵でした！
It was wonderful!
頑張ってね！ありがとうね！
Do your best! Thank you!
バイバーイ！はーい！
Bye-bye! Yay!
ちおー！ちおー！
Chiao! Chiao!
ということで、ひづきちゃんが、来てくれました！
And so, Hizuki-chan came to visit!
ひづきちゃんって言ったの初めてかも！結ちゃんが来てくれました！うれしいね！
It might be my first time saying "Hizuki-chan"! Yui-chan came! I'm so happy!
というわけで、あっという間なんだけど、私、口癖「と、いうわけでなんだの」今気づいちゃった。
So anyway, before I knew it... wait, my catchphrase "So, that's what it is, nano!" I just noticed it now.
ここから、ライブ後半戦です！
From here on is the second half of the live!
それでは、ご曲目、聞いてください！
Now then, please listen to the 5th song!
ねえ、あたし知ってるよ 君が一人涙流しての知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears all alone.
ぐすぐず震えてさ 声も出ないんだわ
Shivering and shaking, unable to make a sound.
正直に言っちゃえばバレてるんだし
To be honest, it's totally obvious,
言っちゃえば効いてんの
and to say it's getting to you—
普通普通平気だよ みんな分かってないだけ無風
It's totally fine, everyone just doesn't get it, it's calm.
ねえ、あたし知ってるよ 君が一人涙流しての知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears all alone.
ぐすぐず凹んでさ 弱音吐いちゃいけないよ
Feeling down and depressed, you shouldn't let out your complaints.
朝が来るまで一緒こうすもん 大人だってなんだだって何度だって受け止めてあげる
We'll stay together until morning. Adults and whatever else, I'll accept you no matter how many times.
もう我慢しないでいっぱいはいってね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
むーわ お願い君が欲しいの 慰めさせて Best Friend 愛の才能で
Muwa, please, I want you. Let me comfort you, Best Friend, with the talent of love,
抱いてくれるかい 君の辛い抱きしめたい ねぇいいでしょ
will you hold me? I want to embrace your pain. Hey, isn't that fine?
わけあって乗り越えたいんだってば
Because we have reasons to overcome it together!
むーわ お願い君が欲しいの 笑い飛ばして Hop Step ジャンプ最高潮で
Muwa, please, I want you. Laugh it off with Hop, Step, Jump at the climax,
褒めてくれるかい 君に思いっきり甘えたい ねぇいいでしょ
will you praise me? I want to pamper myself with you to my heart's content. Hey, isn't that fine?
寄り添って救いたいんだってば
Because I want to stay close and save you!
見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たいの 君の涙
I want to see, see, see, see, see, see, see your tears.
見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たいの 君の笑顔
I want to see, see, see, see, see, see, see your smile.
ねえ、あたし知ってるよ 君が一人悔しがっての知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're feeling frustrated all alone.
ぐすぐず終わるまで 君をけして諦めない
Until it's all over, I'll never give up on you.
ねえ、あたし知ってるよ 君はできる子知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're a capable girl.
辛いときは 弱いくらいでちょうどいい 私君の味方だよ
When times are tough, being a little weak is just right. I'm on your side.
むーわ お願い君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ Instagramで 愛情三畳
Muwa, please, I want you. Call my name, three tatami mats of affection on Instagram.
君が一人か それは違う 一人じゃないもういいでしょ
You're all alone? That's wrong, you're not alone anymore, isn't that fine?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
Solo play is over!
君がどんな時も 私そばにいるわ
No matter what kind of time you're having, I'll be right by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you. That's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
むーわ お願い君が欲しいの 慰めさせて Best Friend 愛の才能で
Muwa, please, I want you. Let me comfort you, Best Friend, with the talent of love,
抱いてくれるかい 君の辛い抱きしめたい ねぇいいでしょ
will you hold me? I want to embrace your pain. Hey, isn't that fine?
わけあって乗り越えたいんだってば
Because we have reasons to overcome it together!
むーわ お願い君が欲しいの 笑い飛ばして Hop Step ジャンプ最高潮で
Muwa, please, I want you. Laugh it off with Hop, Step, Jump at the climax,
褒めてくれるかい 君に思いっきり甘えたい ねぇいいでしょ
will you praise me? I want to pamper myself with you to my heart's content. Hey, isn't that fine?
寄り添って救いたいんだってば
Because I want to stay close and save you!
ねえ、あたし知ってるよ 君が一人涙流しての知ってるよ ぐすぐず凹んでさ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears all alone, feeling down and depressed.
ずっと一緒大人だってなんだだって何度だって受け止めてあげる もう我慢しないで出してんだってば
Always together. Adults and whatever else, I'll accept you no matter how many times. Don't hold back, just let it out!
ということで、新衣装です！みんな可愛い？
And with that, it's my new outfit! Is everyone cute?
気になるとは思うけど、紹介は後で！先にゲストの方と歌うよ！どうぞ！
I'm sure you're curious, but introductions will come later! First, let's sing with our guest! Here we go!
僕らよ 始まれ
Begin, oh us,
青く青く 果てまで
to the blue, blue depths!
繭の底 目をあけたバースデイ
A birthday opening its eyes at the cocoon's bottom,
ホームシックにやられそうなバースデイ
a birthday bound to make you feel homesick.
どこにいてて足りない
Wherever we are, it's not enough,
命はひとつじゃ足りない
one life alone isn't enough.
まだ羽ばたくのは脳内にて
Still, our fluttering is only inside our minds,
終わらせないで まだ不思議な夢を見る
don't let it end yet, seeing strange dreams
二人なら どこまでも行ける
if it's the two of us, we can go anywhere,
とどうしてか信じたくなる
for some reason, I want to believe that.
跳ねる鼓動 誰を呼ぶのベルの音
A leaping heartbeat, whose bell is ringing?
そして待てど 春夏秋冬自分主導
And waiting through the seasons, taking control ourselves.
あっという間に終わる祭りを前に
Before a festival that ends in the blink of an eye,
恐れさえも笑い合おう 共に在ろう
let's laugh even at our fears and be together.
至って不完全体 優位に面白くなってきた
Utterly imperfect, it's becoming wonderfully intriguing.
空腹の夜を越え 空白に願いとまえ
Crossing the hungry night, chanting wishes into the blank space,
諦め尽くされた世界を
a world of total resignation—
君と二人占めに転げ回れ 混ざり合い
roll around claiming it with you, intertwining,
そして生まれ変わるような きっと僕らだけが成せるパレード
and like being reborn, a parade only we can create.
絶対証明したい 進化したい
I want to prove it absolutely, to evolve,
才能を超えた新形態 さあどうなりたい？
a new form beyond talent—now, what do you want to be?
斯くも現実は不可能を敷き詰めたがり 過去の惜別と臆病を小賢しくって嘆くばかり
Reality loves paving over impossibilities, merely complaining of past partings and cowardice.
今はそこに君がいる
Now you are right there,
未知なるバージョン 覚醒前夜
an unknown version on the eve of awakening.
まだ名もなきヒーロー
Still a nameless hero,
行こうか
shall we go?
僕らよ 始まれ
Begin, oh us,
青く青く 果てまで
to the blue, blue depths!
至って不完全体 優位に面白くなってきた
Utterly imperfect, it's becoming wonderfully intriguing.
空腹の夜を越え 空白に願いとまえ
Crossing the hungry night, chanting wishes into the blank space,
諦め尽くされた世界を
a world of total resignation—
君と二人占めに転げ回れ 混ざり合い
roll around claiming it with you, intertwining,
そして生まれ変わるような きっと僕らこそが成せるパレード
and like being reborn, a parade truly we can create.
至って不完全体 尽くしパレード
Utterly imperfect, a full parade!
はーい！お疲れ様です！
Yay! Great job everyone!
その前に ちょっとね 今ね
Before that, just a moment ago...
東北の方で地震があったみたいですが大丈夫でしょうか？
It seems there was an earthquake in Tohoku, is everyone okay?
東北の方、身の回りの安全を優先でお願います！気をつけるんだよ！
To everyone in Tohoku, please prioritize your safety! Please be careful!
そして次のゲストはリオナちゃんでーす！
And our next guest is Riona-chan!
はい！フロクロールのリーダー響咲リョナです！プロプロよろしくね！
Yes! I'm Riona Hibiki, leader of Frocreur! Nice to meet you!
そして空先輩！お誕生日おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
And Sora-senpai, happy birthday! Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
今日はね、あの最近めちゃくちゃ仲良しいっていうのと、仲良し嬉しいですもんね。
Today, well, lately we've gotten super close, and it's great being close.
あと歌とダンスといえば、なんか今はリョナちゃんてイメージがあって。嬉しい！
Also, when it comes to singing and dancing, I think of Riona-chan. I'm so happy!
一緒にね、あの歌いたいと思って歌っちゃいました！本当に嬉しかったですよ！
We really wanted to sing together, so we did! I was so happy!
よりより先輩！なんですか？
Riorio-senpai! What is it?
そうじゃないですか？めっちゃ可愛い！
Isn't that right? It's super cute!
ありがとうございます！どんな衣装なんですか？
Thank you! What kind of outfit is this?
こちらはですね、去年出したアルバムの「PARUS」っていうジャケットで、あの着た衣装なんですけど、
This is an outfit I wore for the jacket of my album "PARUS" released last year,
実際にライブでも着たいと思って仕立てて...
and I had it made because I wanted to wear it in live shows too...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
あら、もうそんな、そらともさんも、もうぴゅーって感じじゃ…あれ？なんか変になっちゃうかもしれない。
Oh my, Sora-tomos might be feeling like... wait? It might turn out a bit weird.
じゃあの、白上さんを見習って、リョナが来た意味をね、今から私もやっていこうと思うんですけど。
So, following Shirakami-san's example, I'm going to start doing the meaning of Ryna coming here.
なんですか？
What is it?
ま、みんなもね、写真がいっぱい撮りたいと思うんですけど、リョナ直伝のセクシーポーズ写真、どうですか？
Well, I think everyone wants to take lots of photos, so how about Ryna's secret sexy pose photos?
やるやる！セクシー大会、こんな大々的な大会ですもんこれは。
I'll do it! A sexy contest, on such a grand scale too.
あのセクシーなポーズを直伝、直伝してくれるのね？じゃあそれをね、そらともさんに
You'll pass on that sexy pose directly? So then, to the Sora-tomos...
写真撮ってもらうっていうかいでも私あの、もう画面外で、え、なんで？
by having them take photos... wait, me? Out of frame, eh, why?
あとで一緒に撮ろうね。あ、オッケーです。じゃあまず、
Let's take them together later. Ah, okay. Well first,
えもやっぱリョナといえば、あ、これはリョナといえば、もうこれですから。
Emo, as for Ryna, ah, speaking of Ryna, well, this is it.
こうできるかな私。これちょっと、ちょっと足をこう、あ、足してくれ、ちょっと、ちょっと、
Can I do this? Let's see, a bit of leg like this, ah, add some, wait, a bit...
あ、いろいろアウト、こういうの、どうですか、こういうの。
ah, various things are out, how is this, this kind of thing?
もうリョナはね、行きますからどっか。あ、いいですね、いいですね。あ、いいです。ちょっと右手前に出しちゃったりして。あ、いいですね、うまい！
Ryna is going somewhere anyway. Ah, nice! Putting your right hand forward a bit. Nice! Skillful!
あれ？そら先輩、セクシーの才能がかなりあるんじゃないですか？おお、素晴らしい！
Huh? Sora-senpai, don't you have quite a talent for sexiness? Oh, marvelous!
え、あとはどうしようかな。ちょっと、あ、いやだ、いいの？そんなセクシーっていうことじゃないのセクシーって。
Eh, what should I do next? Wait, ah, no way, is it fine? Not that kind of 'sexy'.
ま、ちょっと教える必要なかったんですよ、これ。あ、うま、ちょ、あ、ちょっと、上、後ろからのアングルめっしいいな。
Well, I didn't really need to teach you this. The angle from above and behind is really good.
ちょっと、楽しんでないでよ。あ、なんかね、こうこういうのとかね。
Wait, don't just enjoy it. Ah, you know, stuff like this.
やほ、みたいに後ろからの、イェーイ！
Yaho, like from behind, yay!
あ、いいですね、いいですね。かわいい！色とりどりでめっちゃ綺麗ですね。
Ah, nice, nice! Cute! It's colorful and super pretty.
そんなの、グラデーションが入っててかわいいんだよ。めっちゃかわいい！
With that gradation included, it's so cute! Super cute!
え、じゃあ一緒に写ってくれますか？もちろんだよ。そらりおポーズ、考えようって言ったのに全然考えられ
Eh, then will you appear in it with me? Of course! Even though we said let's think of a Sora-Rio pose...
そう、だからそしたらなんか、ほぼ似てるみたいな。そしたら、くまと手で出る、こうっていうの、これ結構いいんじゃないかって思ってるんですけど！
Right, so then it's like, almost similar. So then, bear and hand coming out like this, I think this is pretty good!
ソラリおポーズ、くまのばし、あんきものばし。
Sora-Rio pose, bear stretch, ankimo stretch.
え、あとあれですよ、最近私のこと飲んでるって本当ですか？
Eh, and also, is it true that you've been drinking me recently?
そう！リョナ汁を！貧血のリョナ汁をすごく助かっています。
Yes! Ryna juice! Anemic Ryna juice is a huge lifesaver.
本当ですか？じゃあもういつでも呼び出してください。リョナ、水割りにいくんで。
Really? Then please call me anytime. Ryna will go make it into a water-diluted drink.
あ、ありがとうございます。そら先輩どうぞって。うわあ！助かる！私が助かる！
Ah, thank you very much. Sora-senpai, go ahead. Whoa! Helpful! I'm saved!
いつでもね、補給しますんで、いつでも呼んでくださいね。
I'll resupply anytime, so please call me anytime.
あ、ーい！あれ？お、ちょっと待って！そら先輩、助けて！そら先輩！そら先輩！
Ah, okay! Huh? Oh, wait a minute! Sora-senpai, help me! Sora-senpai!
みんなそれをやっていくんだ！みんなそれをやっていくんだ！
Everyone's going to do that! Everyone's going to do that!
さあ、でもね、リョナちゃんもね本当に仲良くて、いつもね、よく会うんですけど
Now, but you know, Ryna-chan and I get along really well, and we always meet up often...
いつもと変わらない、かわっちい感じでしたね。私がいなくなりましたね、ごめんなさい。お水飲みに行ってました。
it felt just like usual, super cute. I disappeared, sorry. I went to drink some water.
はい、というわけで、続いてのゲストはもう誰だかわかるよね？この人です！
Right, well then, the next guest, you already know who it is, right? It's this person!
GUEST 風真いろは
[Guest: Kazama Iroha]
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告 協和音に酔う 午前零時
A warning sound proclaimed at midnight, intoxicated by harmony at the stroke of midnight.
あなたが触れる 光増す熱 指先に踊らせ
The heat intensifying with your touch, making my fingertips dance.
感覚 即 体感 寝静まる夜 二人だけの密
Sensation, embodiment, a quiet night, just the two of us in secrecy.
体感 即 快感 重なる波形に魅せられていく
Embodiment, sheer pleasure, captivated by overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice,
仮面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
through the mask is fine, love me properly.
バーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual.
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたくて...
I still want to be drowning in your sound...
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
見つめ合う あなたと二人 重ねた
Gazing at each other, the two of us overlapping
きっと 音と響かせ
our breaths and sound, let it resonate.
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
Midnight, asking for the cooled-down heat,
待ち続けている 午前零時
still waiting at midnight.
鏡写しに飽和していく 知らない
Saturated by the reflection in the mirror, an unknown
音が伝わる 感覚 即 体感
sound is conveyed—sensation, embodied experience.
寝静まる夜と息遣い揃う 感覚 即 快感
The night is quiet, and our breaths are in sync—sensation, pleasure.
錆びたロジック 「今一度」を焦がれる
Rusted logic, yearning for "just one more time".
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice,
次元も越えて 飛ばすシグナル
a signal sent across dimensions.
バーチャルなんて言わないで
Don't say I'm virtual,
あなたの音に まだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound.
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
言の葉と初の音が交わる
Words and first sounds intersect—
この息と音と響かせ
overlapping breath and sound, let it resonate.
あなたの生んだ音に
Your first sound,
ただ恋をしていたの
let me hear this voice...
悲しみ 怒り 関心 すべて打ち鳴らす
Sadness, anger, concern, everything is ringing out.
絶えず叫ぶ声 貫ねる
Continually screaming voice, connected.
米津混ぜる愛、絶つ艶めく
Mixing love, enchanting.
絶えず叫ぶ声 貫ねる
Continually screaming voice, connected.
米津混ぜる愛、絶つ艶めく
Mixing love, enchanting.
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice,
仮面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
through the mask is fine, love me properly.
バーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual.
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたくて...
I still want to be drowning in your sound...
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
見つめ合う あなたと二人 重ねた
Gazing at each other, the two of us overlapping
きっと 音と響かせ
our breaths and sound, let it resonate.
あなたの初のれこの声響かせ
Your first sound, let this voice resonate—
あーっ 響かせ
Let it resonate!
はーい！というわけで最後のゲストは、いろはちゃんでーす！
Yay! And our final guest is... Iroha-chan!
いぇーい！ホロックスの！
Yay! Holox's...
強い！
Strong!
イケメン！
Handsome!
早い！
Fast!
かっこいい！
Cool!
うん、なんかすごい 風真いろはでーす！いぇーい！
Yeah, kind of amazing, Kazama Iroha! Yay!
おかしいな？おかしいな？
That's strange. That's strange.
そら先輩。
Sora-senpai.
なに？ お誕生日？
What? Is it your birthday?
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday to you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おかしいな？何がおかしいんだい？
That's strange. What's strange about it?
リハーサルまではあんなにメロついてくれてたのに！
Until the rehearsal, you were so lovey-dovey with me!
すごいじゃん！今日、今日のために整えてくれたってこと？
Amazing! Does that mean you got all set up just for today?
今日のために ちょっとあの整えさせていただきまして。
I got all polished up specially for today.
ありがとうございます！コメント欄のみんなはあんなにメロついてくれてたのにさ、今日は全然メロついてない。
Thank you so much! Everyone in the comments was being so lovey-dovey, but today they're not at all.
いやいやいやそんなことないってよ。「かっこいい二人とも」って書いてあったよ。
No no no, that's not true! It says, "Both of you are so cool."
え、ほんとにすか？ほんとに？
Eh, really? Really?
え、ちょっともう回見たいから「かっこいい」って書いて。
Let's see it again, everyone write "cool".
かわいい、かわいい、かわいい...かわいいのは当たり前じゃん。
Cute, cute, cute... Cute is just natural, right?
あ、そうだよ。そうそうそうそう。風真いろははいつでも可愛い。
Ah, that's right. Exactly. Kazama Iroha is always cute.
「かっこいい」「かっこいい」って。ありがとう！ありがとう、おれたちの「かっこいい」が義務だとしても、風真いろはは嬉しいぞ。
"Cool", "cool"... Thank you! Thank you, even if being "cool" is our duty, Kazama Iroha is happy.
あの、1人でもね、記念配信で歌ってたんだけど、そらすごく似合ってたから一緒に歌いたいなと思ってお願いしちゃいました。
Um, I sang it by myself on my anniversary stream, but since it suited Sora-senpai so much, I wanted us to sing it together and asked her.
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
嬉しくて、嬉しすぎて死んでしまう！
I'm so happy, I could die of happiness!
生きて！生きて！生きて！生きてますよ！
Live! Live! Live! I'm alive!
いや、でもかなうは、やっぱそら先輩って言えばボカロめっちゃ似合うな。
Well, but Kanau—I mean, when you say Sora-senpai, Vocaloid songs suit her so much.
ってずっと思ってたんで、いつかやってくんないかな、オタクとしてって思ってたんですけど、まさか自分がゲストとして！
I've always thought that, wondering if she'd ever do one as an otaku, but never expected to be a guest myself!
そうだよ、呼んでもらえるなんて！こんなありがたいことがあっていいのか！
Exactly, to be invited! Can there be such a wonderful thing?
でもね、一緒に2人で歌ったことがなかったから、歌ってみたくって。
But we'd never sung a duet together before, so I wanted to try it.
確かに！星街ピックだとね、結構ね、ついやってることが多いんですけどね。
True! With Hoshimachi-pick, we often end up doing duets, but...
テストとかでも歌ったけど3人だからデュエットってやったことがなくて。
We've sung in tests and stuff, but there were 3 of us, never a duet.
確かに。
That's true.
ねぇ、有難いお話でございまして本当に。
Yeah, I'm truly grateful for this opportunity.
いやこちらこそ、本当にこの機会を…いやこちらこそありがとうございます！本当に。
No, thank you so much for this opportunity... I mean, thank you so much! Really.
はい！はい！いやそれにしても今日これ新衣装なんですよね。
Yes! Yes! Even so, we're wearing our new outfits today.
そうなんですよ新衣装なんですよ。新衣装なんですよね。どう？
That's right, they're new outfits! Brand new outfits. How do they look?
おおー！おおー！
Whoa! Whoa!
いやちょっと、ま、七草りょうなさんが、なんか結構際どいことやっていたんですけど、
Well, Nanakusa Ryoona-san was doing some pretty daring things earlier,
やはりねあのやっぱあのちょっとこっちのくいこいタイプオタクとしては1個色欲しいでしょうか？
so as an otaku who likes tight outfits, I'd love to see something like that!
なんだろう、やはり男というものはですね、やっぱあの肌脱いだ姿がすごく気になるというものでございまして、
I mean, men are always super curious to see bare skin,
あのこの隠されている純白が、あのこの姿が見れるのかっていうのがすごく気になっておりまして、ええあの本当にだってこの下のなんかもう清潔感あふれるこれ絶対みんな気になるでしょ！
and I've been so curious if we could see that hidden purity... I mean, everyone's definitely curious about the refreshing vibe underneath!
いやオタクとしてもう気になりますよ、こんなの。
As an otaku, you can't help but be curious about this sort of thing!
そうですよね！でも、この本心の中ではちょっとまだ見せないかないう。
That's right! But deep down inside, I guess I shouldn't show it just yet...
え、え、もっともっともしできれば、それは、それは脱げるということでござるか？
W-Wait, if possible, does that mean you'll take it off?
この恥の中では、見せることはないんだけど！
I won't show it in this kind of shyness!
開いた口…いや、人間に灰れ！人間など見れるかもしれないぞ！
Open your... No, enter humanity! You might even see a human!
はい！いや楽しみにしておりますので！こちらこそ！面にに入れ！入れ！
Yes! We're looking forward to it! Same here! Get inside! In!
すっ強制敵…
So coercive...
いやだってこれ、それ、とて、そんな姿が見れるんですよ！
I mean, you can see that kind of appearance!
この後も楽しみにしてますよ！はい！
I'll be looking forward to the rest too! Yes!
というわけで、そら先輩、まだこの後も全然続くと思うんですけど、
Anyway, Sora-senpai, I think this will keep going after this,
頑張ってください！頑張るよ！
please do your best! I'll do my best!
あの、プロとしてお待ちしておりますんで！そうね、また後で！
I'll be waiting as a pro! Right, see you later!
プロとして…プロとして…あ、やばい、プロの世界に引き込まれてしまう！
As a pro... as a pro... Oh no, I'm getting sucked into the world of pros!
ああ、プロの世界に引き込まれ…でも、お値段はね、上品だから、あの、温泉入りは脱がないで！
Ah, sucked into the world of pros... But since the price is classy, um, don't take off the hot spring entry!
ありがとう！ありがとう！未来で待ってる！未来で待っててくれ！
Thank you! Thank you! I'll be waiting in the future! Wait for me in the future!
指なんだ…さあ何を、何をね、あの、また後でってどういうことなんでしょうかね？
It's fingers... Now what, what does "see you later" mean?
はい、プロとして何のプロなんでしょうか？気になる方、あっ配信に来てもらえると
Yes, what kind of pro are they? For those who are curious, if you come to the stream,
嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be really happy.
さて、ちょっと待ってくださいね。いよいよ終盤戦です。
Now, please wait a moment. It's finally the final stretch.
お水美味しい！
Water is delicious!
いよいよ終盤戦なんですけど、最後まで盛り上がってくださいね！
It's finally the final stretch, so please get hyped until the very end!
もしかしたら、あの子が来ちゃうかもね。
Maybe that person might show up too.
聞いてください、プレイ！
Please listen to this, Play!
チョケろ チョケろ さあ準備して
Joke around, joke around, get ready now
いい加減にしろ やめらんないぜ
Cut it out already, I can't stop
どうしようもないね ぶち抜け！
There's no helping it, blast through!
イカれたならあとで考えてくれてやるよ
If you're crazy, I'll think about it later for you
おっと頭が皿ねぇ何回
Oops, my head is empty every time
知識過剰な奴は厄介
Guys with too much knowledge are a pain
みんなが大騒ぎする前にこっちの網に引っかけてきたぜはいはい
Before everyone makes a fuss, I caught you in my net, yeah yeah
どうしたみんな浮かない顔して
What's wrong, everyone looking gloomy?
ええ空手ごと大歓迎よ
Welcome with open arms to the karate thing
現実見ねえよ ぶち抜け！
Face reality? No way, blast through!
はやく楽になりたい
I want to feel at ease quickly
陰惨を女々しさてされ
Gloomy and effeminate, put aside
なんでけーすどえす？ チョケろ チョケろ
Why is it S? Joke around, joke around
さあ準備して いい加減にしろ
Get ready now, cut it out already
やめらんないぜ ハデろ ハデろ
I can't stop, go wild, go wild
責任だって取るよ 墓場までは
I'll take responsibility, all the way to the grave
堂々だけさせてくれ 心のマイベストなトラブルメーカー 取り扱い説明書
Just let me be proud, my heart's best trouble maker, user manual
隅から隅まで読んでおきな ニヤッとしたって なぜか
Read it from corner to corner, even if you smirk, for some reason
ニヤッとしちゃうのおかしな 止めろ止めろ止めろ止めろ
It makes me smirk, how strange, stop, stop, stop, stop
ええ空手ごと大歓迎よ
Welcome with open arms to the karate thing
現実見ねえよ ぶち抜け！
Face reality? No way, blast through!
はやく楽になりたい
I want to feel at ease quickly
陰惨を女々しさてされ
Gloomy and effeminate, put aside
なんでけーすどえす？ 押せよ その理性とぼけて
Why is it S? Push it, play dumb with that reason
消せよ 前のその価値観
Erase your previous values
どうしてなのでも元に戻せるなら ユニコーン見せてるだけじゃつまんないやいやあ
Why is it, but if we can go back to normal, just showing a unicorn is boring, yeah yeah
ああ プロレス さあ お互い思いきり
Ah, pro wrestling, come on, let's both go all out
前のりぎみ 止まる気ないアクセルベタ踏み ねえ愛かね ねえ愛きり はいっ止まってここでストップ プリテンデッドストップ
Leaning forward, accelerator pushed down to the floor without stopping, hey love, hey love, stop right here, stop, pretended stop
絶対やべえよ 話がちげえぞ
Absolutely dangerous, the story is different
はやく楽になりたい 陰惨を女々しさてされ
I want to feel at ease quickly, gloomy and effeminate put aside
なんでけーすどえす？
Why is it S?
逃がした言葉があって
Words that got away,
カタチのない願い多くて
And so many formless wishes,
いつしか手元で湿って重かった
Growing damp and heavy in my hands.
踏み切りは正直どうかと
Wondering honestly if crossing the line is okay,
そうも言えない状況が
In a situation where I can't even say that,
それでも最後ぐらい
Still, I wanted to end it
華やかに終わらせようと
As brilliantly as possible,
全然期待のない夜へ
To a night with no expectations at all.
いざ手放したらまぶしくてさ
Once I finally let go, it was so dazzling,
半信半疑 打ち上げた
Half-believing, half-doubting, I launched it,
正真正銘の気持ちは
A genuine feeling
胸をドンドンどんどんと
Making my chest beat thump, thump, thump.
はーい！ありがとうございましたー！
Hi! Thank you very much!
この曲、トレアイを歌わせていただきましたー！
We got to perform this song, "Treasure"!
そしてこの曲ではなんとサングラスをかけたあんきもがやってきました。
And for this song, Ankimo came along wearing sunglasses!
どうしてサングラス？
Why the sunglasses?
わあ、取れちゃった！
Oh, they came off!
遊ばないの、むい！
Don't play around, mui!
というわけで、久しぶりにね、あんきもと一緒に何か踊った気がするんだけど、どう？
So, it feels like it's been a while since I danced with Ankimo, what do you think?
2人目のゲスト、あんきもです！
Our second guest is Ankimo!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ある意味シークレットだったでしょ？めっちゃ踊るじゃん。
In a way it was a secret, right? You dance so much.
まあ、そんな感じで、
Well, something like that.
まだね、最後にね、実はお披露目もあるんだけど、どう？
Also, there's actually a reveal at the end, how about that?
ここでね、まず恒例のお知らせがたくさんあるので、ここからはあんきもも一緒に告知していくね！
First, there are a lot of our usual announcements here, so Ankimo and I will make them together!
聞いてください。
Please listen.
まずはこちら！「ときのそら 誕生日記念2026グッズ」です！順次紹介していくよ。
First is this! "Tokino Sora Birthday Commemoration 2026 Goods"! I'll introduce them in order.
まずは、こちら！
First, this one!
「Dream！そらともハッピー」イラストはアルダン先生です！テーマはライブをしている私ということでなんとね、あんきももいっぱいいるんだよ。ね！
"Dream! Sora-tomo Happi" illustration is by Arudan-sensei! The theme is me performing live, and there are tons of Ankimos too. Right?
あの、今までもオリジナルハッピー自体は、イベントとかで出たことあるんですけど、自分でオリジナルで作るのは初めてだったので、ぜひライブで来てきてほしいなと思って作りました。
Up until now, original happis have been released at events, but since it's my first time making an original one myself, I made it hoping you'd wear it at lives.
ぜひぜひみんな楽しんでくださいね！ライブに来てください！
Please everyone enjoy it! Come to the live!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
「お部屋でのんびりワイドラバーマット」イェーイ！イラストはシワスタカシ先生です！
"Relaxing in My Room Wide Rubber Mat"! Yay! Illustration is by Shiwastakashi-sensei!
テーマは部屋でファンレターを読んでいる私で、こちらね、ホロカのね、ちょうどいいサイズになってるので、ホロカを遊ぶ方ぜひぜひ一緒にね、あの持って行って遊んでもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
The theme is me reading fan letters in my room. It's sized just right for Holoca, so if you play Holoca, I'd be happy if you take it and play with it.
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
そらとおそろいスマホリング
"Sora-matching Smartphone Ring"!
ということでね、前回販売したDJパーカーとデザインが一緒なので、それとね、一緒に合わせてスマホも私とおそろっちみたいにしませんか？っていう感じです。
The design is the same as the DJ hoodie sold last time, so how about matching your smartphone with mine like we're matching?
そして続いてはこちら！
And next is this!
「そらザウルスなりきりそらちゃんぬいぐるみ」！みんな、みんながあまりにもさ、そらザウルスそらザウルスって言うからさ、でもそらザウルス自体をなんか言うのはちょっと恥ずかしかったから、そらちゃんぬいぐるみ私が着ていることにするなりきりの飾りにしました。
"Sorasaurus Cosplay Sora-chan Plushie"! Everyone kept saying "Sorasaurus" so much, but since saying "Sorasaurus" itself was a bit embarrassing, I made it a cosplay plushie where I'm wearing it.
しかもね、あのね、何そらザウルスって思う人、これ取るとフードがね、取れると、もうピンクの衣装を着てる私みたいになるので、ぜひぜひフードを取り外して可愛らしく持ち歩いてくれてもいいんじゃないかなと思います。
For those who wonder what "Sorasaurus" is, if you take the hood off, it becomes like me in a pink outfit, so I think you can take the hood off and walk around with it cutely.
そして最後はこちら！
And last is this!
ASMRボイス！ボイスタイトル「届いてるよ、きみの応援」
ASMR voice! Voice title: "It's Reaching You, Your Support"
ということで、部屋でファンレターを読んでいるシチュエーションになっておりますので、ぜひぜひみなさん、どんなふうにファンレター読んでいるのかなって想像しながら聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです。
It's a situation where I'm reading fan letters in my room, so I'd be happy if everyone could listen while imagining how I'm reading them.
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと特製ボイス、ボイスタイトルは「誕生日を迎えて」になります。
And the full set purchase bonus is this! A postcard with a hand-signed & foil-stamped message and a special voice titled "Welcoming My Birthday".
というわけですね、あの、みなさん急がなくて大丈夫です。数量限定ではございませんので、みなさん全員分のサインを飾らせていただきます！いくらでも書きますので、ぜひぜひみなさんたくさんの一人グッズを買ってもらえたら私はとってもそらっち大喜びなので、よろしくお願いいたします！
Everyone doesn't need to rush. It's not limited quantity, so I'll write a signature for everyone! I can write as many as you want, so please buy lots of merchandise and I'll be super overjoyed!
以上、ときのそら誕生日記念2026グッズでした！みんなよろしくね！
That's all for the Tokino Sora Birthday Commemoration 2026 Goods! Everyone please look forward to it!
続いてのお知らせはこちら！11月7日ワンマンライブの「ときのそら生誕記念先行チケット販売」開始ということです！
The next announcement is the start of advance ticket sales for Tokino Sora's November 7th solo live!
ピアアリーナのですね、先行チケットが本日からはじまっております！ピアアリーナ、ファンクラブに入ってる人しかできないじゃないかと言ってた人、本日からは一般でみなさんも販売が開始されておりますので、ぜひぜひもう12時から開始されております。
For Pia Arena, advance tickets start today! For those who said you can only get them if you're in the fan club, general sales for everyone have also started today from 12:00.
応募していただけたら嬉しいです！みんなでピアアリーナでライブ楽しもう！
I'd be happy if you apply! Let's all enjoy the live at Pia Arena!
さらにこちら！その現日チケットの特典でもらえるホロカのお披露目、これもお披露目でございました！ライブの来場者特典として限定ホロカが1枚配られます。全2種類のウチ1枚ランダムでお渡しするのですが、そのうちの1枚を公開です！私が書き下ろすということで、もう1個の方はえー...まだなので...
And this! The reveal of the Holoca included with the physical tickets! A limited Holoca will be given as a venue attendee bonus. One of two random types will be given, and we're revealing one of them today! Since I drew this one, the other one is... um, not ready yet...
ぜひこちらのほうで、ちょっと…
Please, won't you...
満足していただけないでしょうか。
be satisfied with this?
そして、9周年ライブを記念して、こちら！
And to commemorate the 9th anniversary live, here it is!
スペシャルテレビCM放送決定ということで、
A special TV CM broadcast has been decided!
本日の22時半から23時の間で、TOKYO MXさんのところで流れます。
It will air tonight between 22:30 and 23:00 on TOKYO MX.
1度だけなので、ぜひ見てくれると嬉しいなと思いますよ。よろしくお願いします。
It's only once, so I'd be so happy if you watch it. Thank you!
そしてそして、最後のお知らせがこちら！
And now, for the final announcement!
お待たせしました。こちらです。
Thanks for waiting. Here it is.
新曲「決意のソラへ」です。
The new song, "Ketsui no Sora e."
私的には、なんかエモい感じの曲とかね、泣き曲かなって思ったんだけど、
Personally, I thought it'd be an emotional or tear-jerking song, but
でも、にれっくすさん的には、もう泣き曲とかエモとかそういう感じじゃない、熱い曲みたいな感じでオープニングにふさわしい感じのぐらいの熱い曲を作ったつもりみたいなこと言ってたので、
Nerext-san said it's not like a crying or emotional song at all, but rather a passionate song fitting for an opening, and that he intended to make it that hot,
このあとMVのプレミア公開も予定されているので、各種音楽サイトでも配信もされています。ぜひたくさん聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです。
so the MV premiere is scheduled after this, and it's also streaming on various music sites. I hope you'll listen to it a lot!
というわけでね、とっても楽しかったんですけど、いかがだったでしょうか。
So yeah, it was a lot of fun, but how was it?
え、そしてですね、え、メインゲームは21時半から、え、アフターライブがあるんですけど、
And also, after the main game at 21:30, there's an after-live,
え、スペシャルあんきもがね、なんとね、見れるかもしれないんだって。
and you might be able to see a special Ankimo!
スペシャルだよ、スペシャル。
A special one, a special one.
もう、このサングラスあんきももスペシャルではあるんだけど、さらにスペシャルあんきも見れるかもしれない。
This sunglasses Ankimo is already special, but you might get to see an even more special Ankimo.
そしてね、さっきも言いました、この、この放送では、まあ、ちょっとまだ逃げないかなって言ってたもの、ありますよね。いろんな撮影しましょう！
And as I said earlier, in this broadcast... there were things where we said "we can't run away yet," right? Let's do various photo shoots!
というわけで、ここまで付き合ってくれてありがとう！あんきもバイバイ！
So, thank you for hanging out with me this far! Bye-bye, Ankimo!
というわけでね、みなさん、いかがだったでしょうか。
So everyone, how was it?
こんなにね、え、いつもの情報の洪水が起こっていると思うのですが、え、ぜひぜひ皆さんあとで見てもらえたら嬉しいです。
I think the usual flood of information is happening again, but I'd be so happy if you all checked it out later.
えー、最後はですね、こんだけ決意のソラへと言っておいて歌わないのはどうかなと思いますので、新曲で締めたいと思います。それでは聴いてください、「決意のソラへ」。
Uh, finally, since I talked all about "Ketsui no Sora e," it'd be weird not to sing it, so I want to close with the new song. Please listen to "Ketsui no Sora e."
一度きりの私の物語は
My once-in-a-lifetime story
運命を超えて煌めくんだ
shines brightly, transcending fate.
行こう
Let's go!
皆さん本日はありがとうございます！とっても楽しかったです！
Thank you all so much today! I had so much fun!
ねえ 私より
You know me better
より私のことを わかってくれる
than I know myself—
キミの存在が
your presence
臆病で泣き虫な心に
gives my cowardly, crybaby heart
勇気と言う魔法をかけたの
the magic called courage.
チクタク
Tick-tock,
時計の針だけが進む 立ち止まってちゃダメだ
only the clock hands move forward. Standing still won't do.
ソラ 転び八起きがお決まりでしょ
Sora, falling down and getting back up is standard, right?
一つ一つ 重ねてきた
One by one, piling up
大切なアルバムをめくるように
like turning the pages of a precious album.
一つ一つ 叶えてきた
One by one, coming true—
今日まで ソラすべてにキミがいてくれたんだ
until today, you've been right there in it all.
終わりのない夢を
An endless dream,
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと追いかけてゆこう 行こう
I will keep chasing it, always and forever. Let's go!
エンスのトレードも果たしてそうで ありがとうございます！
And the MV premiere turned out great too. Thank you!
ねえ ここで笑い合えることが
Hey, being able to smile together here
何よりも大事な真実
is a truth more precious than anything.
チクチク
Prickly, prickly
いたずらなハートが痛む
a mischievous heart aches.
空回り空回り 思考回路フル回転でよーいどん
Spinning around and around, mind racing at full speed, ready, set, go!
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も 大切な人生のストーリーだから
Because even nights spent crying are an important story in life.
夢を夢で終わらせたくないんだ まだ見ぬ景色を 見に行こうよ
I don't want to end this dream as just a dream—let's go see scenery we haven't seen yet!
もっと もっと
More and more,
輝いて
shine brighter!
高く 高く
Higher and higher,
飛び立て 奇跡さえも超えて
take flight, surpassing even miracles!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
皆さんたくさんのコメント ありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for the comments!
一つ一つ重ねてきた 未来地図のページをめくるように
Like flipping through the pages of a future map we've piled up one by one...
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も
Even the nights I cried, cried, and cried
大切な人生のストーリーだから
are a precious story of my life,
夢を 夢で終わらせたくないんだ
I don't want to end this dream as just a dream—
まだ見ぬ景色を 見に行こうよ
let's go see scenery we haven't seen yet!
終わりのない歌を
A song with no end...
キミに キミに キミへと届け
Delivered to you, to you, to you!
ずっと ずっと 誓うの
Forever and ever, swearing...
決意の空へ
to the sky of our resolve...
行こう
let's go!
本当にみんなのおかげで 最高の誕生日になりました！ みんなのこと大好きだよ！ アプサラも来てね！ バイバーイ！
Truly, thanks to everyone, this has been the best birthday! I love you all so much! Come to Azurite too! Bye-bye!